IT BUSINESS ANALYST

Professional Profile

Solution Oriented Business/Requirements Analyst with 2 years of Business/Requirements Analysis experience with background in the Oil and Gas, Banking, Healthcare and Airline sectors. Comprehensive knowledge of complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) from project Inception to completion implementing software development methodologies like the Agile and Waterfall processes. Highly motivated self-starter with excellent analytical, communication, decision making and organization skills. Adept at juggling multiple tasks in high-pressured environments.

Highlights

- Requirement Elicitation and Gathering
- JAD Session Moderation
- Management of Cross-Functional Teams
- Project Management and Tracking
- Change Control Management
- Business Process Modeling
- Enterprise Analysis
- Stakeholder Management and Analysis
- Requirements Traceability Matrix
- Project Risk and Scope Development
- SDLC Methodologies
- Testing, Training and Workshop facilitator

Work Experience

Pearl Companies New Orleans, LA IT Business Analyst 02/2013 to 10/2014

Creation, design and implementation of a Clinical Portal Solution to unite data from 5 separate IT systems (Clinical 5) into a single portal that Doctors and Nurses can view via a wireless connection from anywhere in the Hospital. I was part of a team that was able to effectively coordinate the project, work collaboratively and end up delivering project on schedule and within budget.

- Participated in the **Joint Application Development (JAD) sessions** with the **project sponsors**, **stakeholders and SMEs** to capture the **business and functional requirements**.
- Created and authored the following documentations for the project Functional Requirements Document (FRD), Wireframe, Use case, activity, data flow and process flow diagrams.
- Created and managed the Requirements Traceability Matrix to ensure that the project requirements are met.
- Performed **Gap Analysis** to ensure system initiatives are met.
- Collaborate with the software development teams to propose system/application solutions.
- Run queries in SQL to analyze data and resolve system issues
- Authored **test script** and liaise with QA during testing phase of the project.
- Coordinated and participated in the User Acceptance Testing (UAT)
- Assisted in authoring training manual and employee training.
- Participated actively in the implementation of the new system by working closely with the Change/Implementation Manager to develop and enhance the implementation management process plan.

Iqor Clark, NJ Customer Service Agent 07/2011 to 01/2013

Work in the baggage arrival and Lost and Found areas. Received aircraft and operated passenger loading bridges. Assist customers with quoting fares/schedules. Made reservations. Issue tickets. Check in passengers and baggages on flights, board flights. Resolved disservice situations. Acted as an **SME** during the development of a new window based reservation system (Check-It). Participated in the **UAT testing** of the new system.

First Fidelity Bank Midwest City, OK Depot Sales Manager 12/2008 to 06/2011

PPMC is a subsidiary of Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC) that is responsible for the supply and provision of petroleum products to the domestic markets at minimal operating costs. As a Depot Sales Manager, my duties include:

- Managing business relationships with established customers and prospects.
- Developed new market opportunities.
- Grow the customer base for all products.
- Implement effective sales, business development and customer management strategy programs to maximize revenue generating capacity.
- Work with management articulated strategies for long-term financial viability of the Company.
- Generate detailed business proposals on behalf of prospective and established customers for management consideration and approval.

- Acquisition of new customers for the bank through the creation, development and maintenance of high quality advisory relationships that includes effective consultative selling and creative restructuring of financial solutions.
- Creatively tailor products to meet individual and customer needs.
- Manages credit quality standards through effective management of risk according to the PDDs, Departmental Operating Instructions (DOI) and other SCB/SME policies.
- Work in close partnership with Business Analysts and Credit Managers to ensure that credit applications for new and existing facilities are correctly prepared in accordance with DOI's and PDD's.
- Liaise and provide leadership in areas of expertise, particularly in the provision of products and services to customers.
- Provide feedback to senior management, marketing and product management on customer's needs and the efficiency of marketing strategies and tactics.
- Responsible for preparing weekly, monthly and annual financial reports for management use.

Computer Skills

Microsoft Office Suite (Outlook, Word, Excel, Visio, Access, PowerPoint), Rational Requisite Pro, Rational Clear Quest, Rational Manual Tester & Rational Functional Tester, SQL, Enterprise Architect, Axure, Windows 2000/XP/Vista & Windows 7

Education and Training

Bachelor of Science: Business Administration 1998 The Polytechnic, Ibadan, City, Nigeria

Certificate: Business Analysis 2013 The Training Specialists (Online)

Certifications

Oracle Database 10g Administrator Certified Associate (OCA)